

# - María Cortés Vargas -

## UX/UI DESIGNER | FRONT END DEVELOPER

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a UX/UI Designer and Junior Front-End Developer with a background in architecture. I specialize in creating attractive and functional digital products, focusing on enhancing the user experience and achieving client goals. With a creative and problem-solving approach, I enjoy working in multidisciplinary teams to deliver effective solutions with a unique touch.

# **CONTACT**

+34 663-585081



mariacv1993@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mariacortesv24/



github.com/Mariacortesv



Barcelona, Spain

# **SKILLS**

## Design

- Figma
- · Adobe XD
- Sketch
- · Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- InDesign
- · Final Cut Video

# Front-End

- · HTML5
- · CSS
- JavaScript
- React

## **Development**

- Git
- REST API
- Node.js
- · Agile Methodology

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native)

English (TOEFL)

\*\*\*\*\*\*

Català (A2)

\*\*\*\*\*

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **UX/UI** Designer

Sizigia Consulting

May. 2024 - Now Barcelona, Spain (Remote)

- Designed web applications from concept to launch
- · Created wireframes, user flows, and visual designs for new features and enhancements
- · Developed prototypes and high-fidelity designs
- · Assisted in the design of web and mobile applications
- · Conducted user research
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure user-centered solutions

#### **ARCHITECH**

Roarquitectos

Feb. 2021 - Oct. 2023 Barcelona, Spain

- · Designed interiors for new construction and renovation projects
- · Conducted measurements and prepared budgets
- · Created 3D designs for single-family homes

#### COMMUNITY MANAGER

HIPER MONTIGALA SI

Oct. 2021 - May. 2022 Badalona, Spain

Jan. 2017 - Dec. 2020

Santo Domingo, DR

- · Managed social media and website operations
- Assisted in website maintenance and product functionality
- Developed content for social media, websites, and in-store promotions
- · Supervised sales and shipping processes
- · Ensured effective client communication

#### **ARCHITECH**

Ministry of Education of the Dominican Republic

- · Architectural design for new construction and renovation
- · Measurements and cost estimation

## **EDUCATION**

# **HTL Online Business School**Digital Marketing Course

2024 (6 meses) Barcelona, Spain

# UXCEL

UX/UI Design 2023-2024

Barcelona, Spain

## Develhope

Full Stack Developer

2023-2024 Barcelona, Spain

### **EINA**

Master in Space Design, UX 2020 - 2021 Barcelona, Spain

### PUCMM Architecture

2011 - 2017 Santo Domingo, DR